<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>GOT - WIC</title>
		<description>Game Of Thrones, Winter Is Coming</description>
		<link>/got</link>
		<atom:link href="/got/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Welcome to GOT-WIC</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://got.gtarcade.com&quot;&gt;Game Of Thrones, Winter Is Comming&lt;/a&gt; (GOT-WIT) game, is one of ROS type of games (Realtime Online Strategy). If you want to become a big, powerful player, before anything else, you need to understand much more about this type of game, it’s core mechanics and why and what about this core mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day internet connections could handle tranfering of big data faster, game industry started the concept of online gaming. Why? I will write about it in another post. The very first concept that the industry used, was multiplayer FPS (First Person Shooter) games. It was easy, it was fast to implement, and gamers loved it a lot. But a new game came out that changed everything in the industry, the name? World Of Warcraft (WOW for short).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did WOW do? It was a very simple concept to be honest. You see, up until then, gamers would PAY and buy the CD for game and that was it. The multiplayer - online concept was written in game and the mechanics for the online game play was P2P (peer to peer) and industry and game developers didn’t need to have a server or care about what would happen online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But WOW changed this! You really didn’t need to pay much to have the game, but… The game had many many servers, it was one of the first MMO games out there (massive multiplayer online). For keeping up MMO games, developers need to have servers, maintain those servers, make sure there won’t be any security breach and many more things and all those things, would eat money. So, developers added a very simple concept, a concept that would change the whole game development industry in years to come. Player would be able to BUY items inside the game with real money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First days, when WOW done this, I remember it very clearly. We would laugh and say, who would be stupid enough to spend money all the time just to play a game? But as time passed, day in day out, we would see people coming to caffee nets (some shops that had many computers for people to use and connect to net, good old days) and spend and spend and spend, just to have that hammer or this armor in WOW!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yup, WOW changed everything both for gamers and the industry. I will write more about it later but for time being, lets move on. So, GOT-WIT is an online game, meaning, it has servers, you join those servers and play. Also, it uses the same concept as WOW. Players CAN buy items inside the game with real money (We call the process coining and those who spend money on the game as coiners).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another aspect of the game, is Strategy. Like any other strategy game out there, you will have buildings, tech tree, and army and armor. The more buildings are updated, the better they come. The more tech tree updated, the faster and more powerful some aspects of the game become. And the more everything goes forward, the more advance troops and more powerful army and armor you can have. Simple isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, the last part, REALTIME. I don’t know why, but many people ignore this aspect. As we will write about the game, guides on game play and anything else, here and there, we will come back to this aspect. What is the meaning of realtime? In many strategy games that are available on PC for single player, updating a building won’t take more than few minutes or the most, an hour or two. But in realtime game, oh god, every old and new god, it can take DAYS. Yup, you heared it right, days! I lost the count of servers i played this type of game on them, but as always, I had seen many people who can’t grasp the concept for the game being realtime. The join a new server, and even in the very first week, they are looking for fight after fight after fight. They will never advance that much on building levels, nor the tech tree, why? Because it take ages! Well dude, you are playing a REALTIME game, ofcourse it would take ages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said, I had seen many of these people, they join a new server, play it for a week or two, and as soon as a new server opens afterward, they leave the previous server calling it boring and joining the new server and the loop continues. I know, they like fighting and killing in game, but, don’t we all like that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, these people never understand and feel the joy of end game stage. The call the game boring because the buildings will take lo~ng time to upgrade. But, if you play a single server for some time, eventually you will come to a stage that there is no building left for upgrade! There will come a day that there won’t be any open tech in the tree to upgrade. That is the END STAGE for the game. That is when the real FUN begins! You would go to battle each and every day! You will kill and get your army killed each and every day. You will loose tons of troops, and you would rebuild the number in few days and get your revenge. And this joy, never ends. You won’t need to be concerned about building or tech or armor update any more. Just add more troops on creation stack, and start fighting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2019 13:25:06 -0300</pubDate>
				<link>/got/2019/05/welcom-to-got/</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">/got/2019/05/welcom-to-got/</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
